Koyenikan Olumide Olaolu.

No 2, A Close, 6^{th} Avenue, Federal Housing Estate, Benin City, Edo State.

Tel: +2349063303923 email: olumide.koyenikan@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/koyex1 website: https://koyex1.github.io/portfolio

PROFILE

Worked with several reputable companies and start-ups, where I have managed and effectively overseen huge projects. I am currently a Full Stack Developer, constantly updating my knowledge in several technologies with the hope of becoming extremely good in my field. I have also cultivated the skills and positive attitude to deal with every challenge encountered.

OBJECTIVE

A strong desire to equip myself with the imperative knowledge, skills and abilities required to achieve the depth of knowledge necessary to become an active contributor in my specific field of interest.

PERSONAL DATA

Date of Birth: 1st August 1995.

Sex: Male.

Languages: English

Marital Status: Single.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient in: Java, Python, Javascript. **Intermediate:** C.

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Node JS, React JS.

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB.

Tools: Github, Leetcode, Eclipse, Postman, RESTclient, Jupyter, Anaconda, VS Code

Knowledge of: Algorithm and Data Structure, Numpy, Panda, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn.

Software: Proficiency in GIMP Image Editor, Microsoft Office Tools (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, MS DOS), Picture Manger; Adobe Page Maker, Proteus, MikroC, Windows and Linux PC usage, MATLab.

EDUCATION

University of Benin, Benin City

2012-2017

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical/Electronic Engineering (First class Honors).

University of Benin Demonstration Secondary School, Benin City.

2009-2012

West African Senior School Certificate (WASSC).

Air Force Military School, Jos.

2006-2009

Junior Secondary School Certificate (JSSC).

University of Benin Staff School

2001 - 2006

First School Leaving Certificate

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Procurement Officer (NYSC)

August 2018 – July 2019

Nucleous 3 Energy.

- Procurement of supplies like automation equipment for multinational oil and gas, power, and manufacturing industries in a strategic manner.
- Examine possible unfavorable events through data analysis and prepare control strategies to avert them.
- Find profitable suppliers and commence procurement partnership.
- Transact with suppliers to secure exact material specifications and ensure required documentations are met.
- Strategically negotiate with suppliers to maximize profit.
- Ensure the safe arrival and delivery of packages to the end users.

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2020 - June 2020

Goajo International Educational Consult Ltd.

- Researching, designing, implementing and managing software programs
- Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications.
- Writing and implementing efficient code
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.
- Designing the frontend, building the backend, and ensuring seamless communication between the client and the server points.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Excellent written and oral communication skills.
- Confidence and Re silience to get things done with little supervision.
- Energetic and easily adaptable under pressure.
- Excellent interpersonal skills.

- Self-motivated and detail-oriented.
- Matured team playing ability.
- Curious, enthusiastic and fast learning.
- Creative approach to solving problems.
- Highly dedicated to work and adaptive to any working condition.

HOBBIES

Swimming; playing piano; playing board games; reading; watching soccer, tech shows and documentaries.